Do you have what it takes to stop me?
你有...
Just as
就跟
Askeladd did back then?
阿谢拉特那时一样?
Please leave, Thorfinn.
你走吧 托尔芬
You're a strange guy, but I don't want to kill you.
你很奇怪 但我不想杀了你
This is how the world works.
这就是世界的运作法则
In the end, whoever has more power always gets their way.
到头来 谁权力更大 谁就能得其所愿
Damn Vikings...
该死的维京人
How foolish of you, my son.
你真傻啊 我的孩子
You're still hesitant of becoming a full-fledged king?
你仍然无法下定决心 成为独当一面的王者吗?
Why did you reveal your honest feelings
你为什么要对一个这么下贱的人
to such lowly people?
流露你的真实情感呢?
I hope you didn't think that you could possibly understand each other.
我希望
They are a pitiful flock of sheep.
他们就是一群可怜的羊
You are a lone shepherd.
你是孤独的牧羊人
You raise them, cull them, and skin them.
你饲养它们、挑选它们 然后把羊皮剥了
The work of a shepherd cannot be understood by the sheep.
牧羊人的工作
You rule over them, that's all there is to it.
你统领它们 就是这么简单
That is the best thing you can do for the sheep.
这是对羊群最好的安排
Canute...
库奴特
If you intend to use your authority to forcefully get your way...
如果你打算用你的权力
Kill him.
杀了他
That man is a threat.
那个人是个威胁
One sheep can confuse the flock
一只羊就能够迷惑整群羊
and send them running off a precipice.
让它们从悬崖上往下跳
I will...
-我会... -杀了他
Fulfill your duty as the king.
尽到做国王应尽的责任
I will...
我会...
run.
逃跑
Run?
逃跑?
That's it?
就这样?
What else can I do?
我还能做什么?
Do you want us to kill each other here or what?
你难道想要 我们在这里拼个你死我活吗?
The paradise you speak of
你口中的天堂
saves the majority
拯救了绝大多数的人
and oppresses a few.
压迫了一些人
That's the way it is, right?
世道就是如此 对吧?
I can't say if that is good or bad.
我无法评判对错
And I have no right to condemn your recklessness.
我也没有权力谴责你鲁莽
So I have no choice but to run away.
所以我别无选择 只能逃跑
- Einar, let's go. - You are excellent.
-埃纳尔 走吧 -你是一位...
As a warrior.
了不起的战士
You must have other options.
你一定有其他的选择
Did you
你来到
appear before the emperor
帝王面前
just to admonish me?
只是为了告诫我?
You got your face swollen for that?
你被打得鼻青脸肿只为了这个?
And it was all a waste.
全都是白忙一场
Goodbye,
再见
Your Majesty.
陛下
So many...
有这么多...这么多人想跟我讨价还价
Some even try to set me up.
有些人甚至对我设下圈套
But...
但是...
What is up with you?
你是怎么搞的?
You are such an idiot!
你真是个笨蛋
You have nothing up your sleeve?
你就只有这点能耐?
You came here completely unarmed and you got beaten to a pulp
你手无寸铁地来到这里 被打得面目全非
just to tell me to stop seizing this farm?
只是为了当面告诉我 要我不要征收这座农场?
Is it that funny?
有这么好笑吗?
It is.
对
This is the stupidest peace negotiation I've ever experienced.
这是我遇过最蠢的和平谈判
You're going to run, huh?
你要逃跑 是吗?
Yeah.
对
Someone like him
一个像他这样的人
can come from Vikings, huh?
竟然是维京人?
What a beautiful man.
是一个拥有美丽心灵的男子
You will turn your back on conflict.
你要避开冲突
Then run to where?
-逃去哪里? -除了这里以外的地方
I can't tell you about it.
我没办法告诉你是哪里
My territory is constantly expanding.
我的领土一直在扩张
In time,
总有一天
my authority may reach there too.
我的权势也会抵达那里
I'll keep running as long as I can.
我会不停地逃跑
As long as there is a place to run to,
只要我仍然能够找到容身之处
I will not fight.
我不会抵抗
I will build a land of peace
我会打造一个和平之地
in a place out of the king's reach,
王权到不了的地方
using an approach different from you.
用一个跟你完全不同的做法
For the people who cannot
为那些无法生活在
live in the world you create.
你建造出来的这个世界的人
For your sake, and my sake as well.
为了你
Are you saying that you will fill in the gaps
你的意思是说你能够填补
that my project can't fill?
我计划的漏洞?
Are you capable of that?
你办得到吗?
My power is much smaller compared to yours.
我的力量
I can't handle a gap that is too big.
如果漏洞太多 我也处理不了
If you continue to persecute people like this,
如果你继续像这样压迫人民
nobody will be able to help you anymore.
再也不会有人帮得了你
So you better try your best too.
所以你也得尽力而为
Don't give me more work to do.
别让我太辛苦
My goodness...
我的天
You really learned how to use your words.
你真的变得很会说话
I wonder who you got that from.
我纳闷你是向谁学的
Interesting.
很有意思
This is the most difficult peace negotiation I've ever experienced.
这是我遇过
What... in... the world?
这究竟是怎么回事?
Even the ships are gone?
连船都没了?
Where did you go, King Canute?
库奴特王 您要去哪里?
This is ridiculous!
太荒唐了
We still haven't settled this!
这件事
Floki was grumbling.
弗洛基抱怨个不停
He can't comprehend why we're withdrawing from the farm.
他无法理解我们为什么要从农场撤退
Are you also unhappy about it, Wulf?
你也不开心吗 沃尔夫?
Not at all.
完全没有
I will call off our plans of requisitioning other farms as well.
我也会取消其他的农场征收计划
I'd feel bad if I gave Thorfinn more work to do.
如果我让托尔芬太辛苦 我会过意不去
Up until now,
在这之前
I thought you were the only one
我一直以为
who was fighting alongside me.
与我并肩作战的人只有你
But today,
但今天
I found a new comrade.
我找到了一位新同志
After this, Canute
之后 库奴特
disbanded the Danish troops that were
解散了部署在英格兰
stationed in England and proving to be a financial burden.
耗尽国库的丹麦军队
Ultimately, Canute's personal force of Danish troops
最终
was reduced to one fleet of just 16 ships.
缩减到一个只剩下16艘船的舰队
However, they did not face any rebellions within England
但是 英格兰并未如预期地
like they anticipated.
发动叛乱
Because Canute relinquished military power,
因为库奴特放弃了兵权
the peers of England came to see Canute's trust.
英格兰诸王感受到 库奴特对他们的信任
The relationship between the conqueror and the conquered
征服者与被征服者之间的关系
was starting to change.
开始改变了
It feels good.
感觉真好
As long as you're alive...
只要你还活着
you can start again...
就能够重新开始
Why do I have to live?
我为什么要活着?
Thorfinn...
托尔芬
- You're all better now? - Yeah.
-你好多了吗? -对
I'm still a little wobbly,
还是有点肿
but I'm okay.
但没什么大碍
Stop being so reckless.
别再这么鲁莽行事了
Sorry.
对不起
Are you going, Thorfinn?
你要去哪里 托尔芬?
To a land on the other side of the sea?
去寻找海洋另一边的土地吗?
It's Vinland.
那是文兰
Vinland...
文兰...
At that moment,
在那一刻
when Arnheid
当阿奴纳
took her last breath,
咽下最后一口气的时候
I couldn't give an answer right away.
我没办法立刻回答她
Why
为什么
do they have to live?
他们得活下去
These souls
这些灵魂
live through hell and seek peace in death.
经历过重重磨难 在死亡里找到和平
What can you possibly say to them?
你还能够对他们说什么?
I want a world where we can tell them to live.
我想要一个让我们能够 要他们活下去的地方
A place where we can confidently say that to people who don't have
让我们能够自信满满地要求那些 只能用死寻求解脱的人
any escape other than death.
活下去的地方
A place that overshadows the appeal of death.
一个比死更吸引人的地方
I want that in our world.
我希望这个世界上有这么一个地方
That is all...
这就是...
That is all we ever wanted.
我唯一的梦想
I can't back down.
我没办法回头了
If it doesn't exist...
如果这个地方不存在
If it's not there, I'll make it.
如果没有这种地方 我会创造出来
Einar...
埃纳尔
Come with me, my brother.
兄弟 跟我一起去
We're going to make a land of peace in Vinland.
我们要打造出 这个叫做文兰的和平之地
Somewhere we can proudly tell Arnheid about.
一个让我们能够 骄傲地告诉阿奴纳的地方
Let's do it, my brother. Let's go to the other side of the sea
兄弟 就这么做吧 我们航向海的另一边
and create a land where there are no slaves or war.
创造一个没有努力没有战争的地方
For Arnheid.
为了阿奴纳
Are you sure
你确定
you're okay with this?
你要这么做?
It wasn't my place to do that anyway.
那种事根本就不该由我出面
I'll tell the master and everyone else
我会告诉主人和其他人
that the young master was the one who persuaded the king.
是少主说服了国王
That'll be great.
那就太好了
You can leave Arnheid's grave to me.
阿奴纳的坟就交给我吧
I will protect it.
我会好好保护它
Thank you so much.
真的感激不尽
It's nothing.
没什么
Thorfinn, I want to become like you.
托尔芬 我想成为像你这样的人
I want to become
我想成为
a real man who is strong and kind, like you.
跟你一样勇敢仁慈的真男人
Olmar, I heard
欧玛 我听说
that you made the decision to stop fighting.
你做出了停战的决定
That is a wonderful thing.
实在是太棒了
It took me 15 years.
我花了15年
But...
但是...
I finally know what I am supposed to do.
我终于知道该怎么做了
This is a wonderful farm.
这是一座很棒的农场
Please get it back on its feet and protect it.
请恢复农场本来的样子 好好保护它
Old master,
老主人
thank you very much.
非常感谢您
You always helped us out.
您一直在帮助我们
There is nothing for you to thank me for.
你没有什么好向我道谢的
I wish they took at least one silver mark.
我希望他们
Thorfinn! Einar!
托尔芬、埃纳尔
My name is Roald! I am Roald, son of Grim!
我叫罗德
Thank you, Roald!
谢谢你 罗德
I wish you all the best!
大家要保重啊
Come here.
过来
Good boy.
乖孩子
ENGRAVE IT
刻吧
ENGRAVE IT UPON YOUR BODY ENGRAVE IT UPON THE LAND
(刻在你身上 刻在这片土地上)
ENGRAVE IT UPON THE SEA
(刻在大海上)
ENGRAVE IT UPON YOUR LOOT ENGRAVE IT UPON YOUR ENEMY
(刻在战利品上 刻在敌人身上)
ENGRAVE IT
(刻吧)
Hey, when are you going to start working, Boss?
老大 你什么时候才要开始工作?
- Come on! - Oh, quit yapping.
-快点 -别再闲聊了
I was just taking a break.
我才刚刚开始休息
I'll show you how to really work a field.
我来教教你们该怎么种田吧
Oh, then why don't you show us?
那你为何不亲自下地?
I'll finish this before you know it.
我会用飞快的速度完成
ENGRAVE ITS TEXTURE UPON ME
(把触感刻在我身上)
My life
我这辈子
has always been about enduring,
一直都在忍受
I thought the countless hardships were part of living in this world.
我以为活在世上
Would you have guessed that
你意料得到吗?
we would meet people like those two, Arnheid?
我们竟然会遇见那两个人 阿奴纳?
They're on their way...
他们上路了
to a world that we can't even imagine.
前往一个我们甚至无法想像的地方
To a place other than here.
跟这里
ENGRAVE THAT ENCOUNTER UPON ME
(把那场际遇刻在我身上)
"Hometown."
故乡
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒